ADAMU M. DANKORE

2107 Clark ST, Charles City, Iowa 50616 || (319) 296-5799 adamu.dankore@gmail.com || https://www.dankore.com

SUMMARY-

An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in JavaScript, React, Ruby, MongoDB, Express, Node, marketing and launching startups. Strong engineering and design professional with over 12 million impressions of design work on Facebook.

TOOL STACKS / COMPETENCIES-

JavaScript • Node.js • React • Express • Ruby • MongoDB • Front-End Web Development • Back-End Web Development • Data Structures • Bootstrap • Tailwind CSS • HTML5 • CSS3 • NoSQL • Object Oriented Programming • GitHub • Gitlab • Marketing • Design • LucidPress • Social Media Marketing • Version Control • Problem Solving • Client/Server Side • Ajax • Management • MVC Architecture • Databases • Slack • Troubleshooting • JSON • REST API • Modern Web Security • GIT • SEO • Aseptic Technique • Teamwork • SAP • JSX • SPA • SQL • Access • VBA

EXPERIENCE -

HOME AWAY FROM HOME

Remote, part-time 2018-Present

- Software Engineer & Head of Marketing
 - Lead a small marketing team which grew the startup to 4,000 unique visits and 400,000 SSL requests a month*
 - Added, modified, and created new pages to the site's single-page-application
 - Designed and implemented views using Tailwind CSS
 - Improved user experience through product design and content addition

CAMBREX INC

Charles City, Iowa 2017-Present

Process Support Chemist

- Perform chemical testing using HPLC, GC, NMR, FTIR, UV-VIS, and more
- Authorized to perform tests on more than 2000 methods including USP and EP
- Pharmaceutical cGMP API environment
- Work with high potent compounds such as opioids and narcotics.
- Adhere to EP, DEA, and FDA regulations
- Our site saved the company more than Seven Million U.S. Dollars since 2017 to date

FREELANCE-

Software Engineer and Designer

2018-Present

- Designed & developed custom websites and Facebook Camera Effects for clients based on specifications
- Collaborated and worked iteratively with clients to determine the necessary project requirements

PROJECTS

GSS GWARINPA NETWORK | http://www.gssgwarinpa.com

- Developed a social networking app for current and past students of my former secondary school
- Implement modern web security features to protect users' personal data
- The site has been receiving positive feedback from students and alumni and continues to grow day-by-day

EMAIL APP | CAMBREX INC

- Initiated, designing, and developing an internal company app that would allow employees to send emails
- The project would help provide a uniform reporting template therefore improving communication amongst employees

EDUCATION-

WARTBURG COLLEGE, Waverly, Iowa **B.A Chemistry; Minor, Leadership,** 2012

OTHER-

*As of August, 2019